A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1975-1976
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1975-1976
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.781
This collection consists of 10,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred on 1978 August 9.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
Organization
Series I: General Records, 1975-1976 Boxes 1-25
Series II: Administrative Committees, 1975-1976 Boxes 25-26
Contents List
- Series I: General Records
  - "A-Al" Miscellaneous 1975-1976 (Box 1)
    ABC TV, ACTION, Shift of Adult Education to Lane High School, Albemarle Sheriff's Office Antenna on Observatory Mountain, Alcoa Foundation Scholarship, Baccalaureate Invitation to Alan Alda, Alpha Phi Alpha re: Farmington and Minority Students
  - "Am" Miscellaneous 1975-1976 (Box 1)
    American Civil Liberties Union Meeting to Discuss the Honor System; Correspondence, Invitations from and Information on Various National Associations, such as American Cancer Society, American Council of Learned Societies, etc.
  - "An-Az" Miscellaneous 1975-1976 (Box 1)
    Anderson Brothers Book Stores' Contribution to Birdsong Chair, Newcomb Hall Bookstore; Correspondence of Several Associations
  - Admissions--General 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--Personnel 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--Undergraduate Schools "A-B" (2 folders) (Restricted) 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--Undergraduate Schools "C-Han" (5 folders) (Restricted) 1975-1976 (Box 2)
  - Admissions--Undergraduate Schools "Har-Ne" (5 folders) (Restricted) 1975-1976 (Box 3)
  - Admissions--Undergraduate Schools "Ni-Z" (5 folders) (Restricted) 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Admissions--Law "L-W" (Restricted) 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - Admissions--Medical (2 folders) (Restricted) 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - Admissions--Sensitive Cases (Restricted) 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - Air Force Academy 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - Alumni Association 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - Alumni Fund 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - Alumni Fund File for Clay Delauney, Director of the Alumni Fund 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - American Association of State Colleges and Universities 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - American Association of University Professors 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - American Council on Education 1975-1976 (Box 5)
  - American Council on Education 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Annual Reports 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Annual Reports--President 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Annual Reports--President--Letters Received 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Anthropology 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Applications for Positions 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Architecture--General--Visit by Chinese Architects, Proposed Name Change for Division of City Planning 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Architecture--Personnel 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Army--General 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Army--Judge Advocate General's School 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Art--General 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Art--Bayly Museum, Woodward Foundation Painting, Tadesty Painting, Gifts to Museum 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Art Commission 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Asian Studies Consortium 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Association of American Colleges 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Association of American Universities 1975-1976 (Box 6)
  - Association of American Universities 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Astronomy 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Athletics--General (2 folders) 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Athletics--Atlantic Coast Conference (ACC) 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Athletics--Finances 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Athletics--National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Athletics--Personnel 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Attorney General--State 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - Automated Data Processing 1975-1976 (Box 7)
  - "Ba-Be" Miscellaneous 1975-1976 (Box 8)
    Bacon, Mrs. Fredericks re: Davidge Randall-McIver; Barber, Mrs. John W. re: the Rotunda; Bate, Dr. John T. re: Proposal to reconstruct the Anatomical Hall; Bemiss, Fitzgerald re: China Seminar; Bernhardt, Lawrence D. re: William Ronald Paintings
  - "Bi-Bz" Miscellaneous--Black Student Alliance re: an Office of Minority Affairs; Brooks Hall Fire Safety Regulations 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Bicentennial (2 folders) 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Biology--General 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Biology--Personnel 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Budget--General 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Budget--Capital Outlay 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Budget--Medical 1975-1976 (Box 8)
  - Budget--Presentation by Hereford for 1976-1978 Biennium 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Buildings and Grounds--General 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Personnel 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Bursar 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Business and Finance 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Business Manager 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - "Ca-Ck" Miscellaneous--Visit of Canada's Governor-General; Carnegie Foundation; Chappel, Warren 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - "Cl-Com" Miscellaneous--Clark Memorial Fund 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - "Con-Cum" Miscellaneous--Consortium on Financing Higher Education, Copenhagen Boys' Choir 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Career Planning and Placement 1975-1976 (Box 9)
  - Cavalier Daily--Honor Committee, Report to Vice President on Student Affairs re: Student Publications and Broadcasting, Young Americans for Freedom, James J. Kilpatrick 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Center for Advanced Studies 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Chemistry 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Civil Rights--Handicapped Legislation 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Clinch Valley College--Paramount Coal Company Lease 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - College of Arts and Sciences 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - College Entrance Examination Board 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Commerce--General 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Commerce--Personnel 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Community Colleges 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Comptroller--University 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Comptroller--State 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Computing Activities 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Consortium--General 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Consortium--Central Virginia 1975-1976 (Box 10)
  - Consortium--Northern Virginia 1975-1976 (Box 11)
  - Consortium--Northern Virginia--Report and Recommendations of Administration 1975-1976 (Box 11)
  - Consortium--Tidewater 1975-1976 (Box 11)
  - Consortium--Valley of Virginia 1975-1976 (Box 11)
  - Consortium--Western Virginia 1975-1976 (Box 11)
  - Continuing Education 1975-1976 (Box 11)
  - Council of Presidents 1975-1976 (Box 11)
  - Council of Southern Universities 1975-1976 (Box 11)
  - "D" Miscellaneous--Downing College, Cambridge Exchange Fellowship; DuPont Gift; Durrette, Wyatt B. re: Rape Problem 1975-1976 (Box 11)
  - Danforth Foundation 1975-1976 (Box 11)
  - Darden Graduate School of Business Administration 1975-1976 (Box 11)
  - Darden Graduate Business Sponsors 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Dean's Meetings 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Development 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Development--Personnel 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Drama 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - "E" Miscellaneous--Educational Testing Service, Ewald Gift, Exxon Gift 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Economics 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Education--General--Dedication of Ruffner 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Education--Personnel 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Energy Office--State 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Energy Research and Development Administration 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Engineering and Applied Science--General--Coordination of Finals Activities, Accreditation of Programs by Engineers' Council for Professional Development 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Engineering and Applied Science--Personnel 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Engineering and Buildings 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Engineering--Research Laboratories for the Engineering Sciences (RLES) 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - English 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - English, Doctor of Arts--Proposal for a Planning Grant 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Enrollment 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Environmental Sciences 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - "F" Miscellaneous--Fahnestock Bequest, Food Services, Medal Presented by French Embassy 1975-1976 (Box 12)
  - Faculty--General 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences--General 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences--Meetings 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Faculty of Arts and Sciences--Personnel 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Federal Executive Institute 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--DuPont Regional 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--Fulbright 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships--Love 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Financial Aid to Students 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Ford Foundation 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - French Literature and Linguistics 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - "Ga-Go" Miscellaneous--Gellman Gift to Gooch Fund, General Electric Gift, German-American Conference, Gillison Land Case 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - General Assembly 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - General Assembly--House Appropriations 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - George Mason University 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Germanic Languages and Literature 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Gifts and Grants 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Government and Foreign Affairs 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Governor--General 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Governor--Administrative 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - Governor--Education 1975-1976 (Box 14)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1975-1976 (Box 14)
  - Graphics Communications 1975-1976 (Box 14)
  - Guggenheim Foundation 1975-1976 (Box 14)
  - "Ha-Hol" Miscellaneous--Hadow, Josephine re: Easters Harassment; Hagan, James re: Gift of Sculpture; Hamilton, Hugh S. re: Gift; Harrison, Henry T. re: Honor System; "Honor Men"; Holton, Linwood 1975-1976 (Box 14)
  - "Hon-Hux" Miscellaneous--Honeywell Gift, Housing 1975-1976 (Box 14)
  - Health, Education and Welfare (2 folders) 1975-1976 (Box 14)
  - Hereford, Frank L. 1975-1976 (Box 14)
  - Hereford--Correspondence re: Farmington Decision (2 folders) 1975-1976 (Box 14)
  - Hereford--Correspondence re: Farmington Decision (6 folders) 1975-1976 (Box 15)
  - Hereford--Newspaper Clippings re: Farmington Issue 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - Highway Department 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - History--Lack of Funds for Students 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - History--Personnel--Correspondence re:Woodford McClellan's Wife in Russia 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - Honor System and Committee--Questionnaire, Poll 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - Housing 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - "I" Miscellaneous--Inter-fraternity Council 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - Institute of Government--Local Government Officials' Conference 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - Institutional Analysis 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - Irano-American Center--Draft Proposal 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - International Students 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - "J" Miscellaneous--Jefferson Society 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - Judiciary Committee 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - "K" Miscellaneous--Honor Code at West Point; Kilpatrick, James J., Kooniz, W. W., Early American Furniture Collection 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - "L" Miscellaneous--Lambeth Field Access; Lewis, Jerry 1975-1976 (Box 16)
  - Law--General 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Law--Alumni 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Law--Center for Oceans Law and Policy 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Law--Personnel 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Law School Foundation 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Law Enforcement Education Program 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Lawn Society 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Legal Advisor 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Library--General--Hugh Scott Gift, J. Pratt Papers, Weedon Gift, Insurance Settlement for Book Theft 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Library Associates 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Library--Center for Research Libraries 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Library--Personnel 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous--McConnell Gift 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - "Ma-Me" Miscellaneous--Rotunda Furnishings 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - "Mi-Mz" Miscellaneous--Minority Business Bids and Contracts 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - McGregor Fund 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - McIntire Fund 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Madison House 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Marine Science 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Mariners Museum 1975-1976 (Box 17)
  - Mary Washington College 1975-1976 (Box 18)
  - Mathematics 1975-1976 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center--General 1975-1976 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center--Hospital 1975-1976 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center--Hospital--Personnel 1975-1976 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center--Nursing 1975-1976 (Box 18)
  - Medical Center--Nursing--Personnel 1975-1976 (Box 18)
  - Medical School--General (2 folders) 1975-1976 (Box 18)
  - Medical School--Advisory Committee 1975-1976 (Box 18)
  - Medical School--Clinical Faculty Fees 1975-1976 (Box 18)
  - Medical School--Personnel 1975-1976 (Box 18)
  - Music 1975-1976 (Box 18)
  - "N" Miscellaneous-- New Literary History1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - National Aeronautics and Space Administration 1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (NASULGC) 1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (NASULGC)--Advancement of Public Negro Colleges 1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (NASULGC)--For Your Information 1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities 1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - National Medal of Science 1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - National Science Foundation 1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - Naval Academy 1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - Newcomb Hall 1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - Newcomen Society 1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - Omicron Delta Kappa 1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - "P" Miscellaneous--Centralized Police System Proposal 1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - Parking and Transit 1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - Personnel Department 1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - Personnel--Employee Relations 1975-1976 (Box 19)
  - Personnel--Position Approvals (2 folders) 1975-1976 (Box 20)
  - Personnel--Position Requests 1975-1976 (Box 20)
  - Personnel--State 1975-1976 (Box 20)
  - Personnel--University 1975-1976 (Box 20)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1975-1976 (Box 20)
  - Philosophy 1975-1976 (Box 20)
  - Physics--General 1975-1976 (Box 20)
  - Physics--Personnel 1975-1976 (Box 20)
  - Planning Department--University 1975-1976 (Box 20)
  - Planning--State 1975-1976 (Box 20)
  - Project Status Reports 1975-1976 (Box 20)
  - Promotions 1975-1976 (Box 20)
  - Provost 1975-1976 (Box 20)
  - Psychology 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - Purchasing 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - "Ra-Re" Miscellaneous--Task Force on Rape, Readers' Digest Article 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - "Ri-Ro" Miscellaneous--Richardson, Elliot; Rotunda Furniture 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - Recommendations 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - Registrar 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - Religious Studies--Proposal for Ph.D. Program 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - ROTC--General 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - ROTC--Air Force 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - ROTC--Army 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - ROTC--Navy 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - "Sa-Sol" Miscellaneous 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - "Som-Sz" Miscellaneous 1975-1976 (Box 21)
  - Safety and Security 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - Senate--University 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - Seven Society 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - Slavic Languages 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - Sociology 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - Southern Fellowship Fund 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - Southern Regional Education Board 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - Space Administrator 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - Spanish, Italian, and Portuguese 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - Speech Communication 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - Speeches--President's Current 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - Sponsored Programs 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - State Council of Higher Education (SCHE) (3 folders) 1975-1976 (Box 22)
  - State Council of Higher Education (SCHE) 1975-1976 (Box 23)
  - State Department of Education 1975-1976 (Box 23)
  - State, United States Department of 1975-1976 (Box 23)
  - Student Affairs 1975-1976 (Box 23)
  - Student Council 1975-1976 (Box 23)
  - Student Council Funding 1975-1976 (Box 23)
  - Student Council Minutes 1975-1976 (Box 23)
  - Student Health Department 1975-1976 (Box 23)
  - Summer Session 1975-1976 (Box 23)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1975-1976 (Box 23)
  - Taliaferro vs Dykstro 1975-1976 (Box 23)
  - Tayloe Murphy Institute 1975-1976 (Box 23)
  - Travel Invoices--Hereford 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - Treasurer 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - Universities Research Association 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - University Center in Virginia 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - University Police 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - University Press of Virginia 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - University Relations 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - University Relations--Medical Center Information 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - University Union 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - Upward Bound 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - Urban Observatory Program 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - Virginia Student Aid Foundation 1975-1976 (Box 24)
  - "W-Wh" Miscellaneous 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - "Wi-Wz" Miscellaneous 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - "X-Y-Z" Miscellaneous 1975-1976 (Box 25)
- Series II: Administrative Committees
  - Admissions 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Arboretum 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Architectural Advisory 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Archives and Records Advisory 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Athletic Advisory Council 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Calendar 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Career Planning and Placement 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Catalogue 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Cemetery 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Chapel 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Community Colleges 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Computers 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Danforth Fellowships 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Educational and Employment Opportunities, Obligations, and Rights 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Special--Energy Conservation 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Fraternities and Sororities 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Fulbright Grants 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Future of the University 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Graduate Opportunities 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Graphics 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Gwathmey Award 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Housing 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - International Students 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - Lectures--Page, Barbour, and Richard 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Lectures--Special 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Library 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Master Plan 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Minority Student Affairs Advisory Council 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Names 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Patents 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Processions 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Public Occasions 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Radiation Safety 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Radiation Safety--Subcommittee--Radioactive Drug Research 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Registration 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Rhodes Scholarships 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - ROTC 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Scheduling 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Scholarships, Grants-in-Aid, Loans, and Employment 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Security and General Safety 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Student Activities 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Student Health 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Student Rights and Responsibilities 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Summer Grants 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Summer Sessions 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Teacher Education 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Thomas Jefferson Award 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Traffic and Parking 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Traffic Appeals 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - University Committee on Students 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - University Press 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - University Union 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1975-1976 (Box 26)
  - Virginia Status University Students 1975-1976 (Box 26)